<metadata xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions" xmlns:xdt="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-datatypes"><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Hudson County Department of Planning</origin><pubdate>20130521</pubdate><title>Parcels of Hudson County, New Jersey State Plane NAD83</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Secaucus, New Jersey</pubplace><publish>Hudson County Department of Planning</publish></pubinfo><onlink>https://njgin.state.nj.us/NJ_NJGINExplorer/DataDownloads.jsp</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>
This parcels data set is a spatial representation of municipal tax lots for Hudson County, New Jersey.

The data set was updated and normalized between 2009 - 2011 as a component of the New Jersey Office of Information Technology, Office of GIS (OGIS) Parcels Normalization Project to develop a statewide composite of parcels data.  During this project, parcels were modified at municipal boundaries to conform to the spatial framework of the OGIS Municipalities of New Jersey (nj_munis) data set, and attributes were modified to conform with the New Jersey GIS Parcel Mapping Standard.

Each parcel contains a unique identifier based on a county/municipality code, block number, lot number and qualification code.  Using the unique identifier, the data set can be joined to MOD-IV database tables that contain supplementary attribute information regarding lot ownership and characteristics.

Due to irregularities in the data development process, duplicate PAMS_PIN values exist in the parcel records.  Users should avoid joining MOD-IV database table records to all parcel records with duplicate PAMS_PINs because of uncertainty regarding whether the MOD-IV records will join to the correct parcel records.

There are also parcel records with unique PAMS_PINs for which there are no corresponding records in MOD-IV database tables.  This is mostly due to the way data are organized in the MOD-IV database.

Parcels are not survey data and should not be used as such.  The polygons delineated in this data set do not represent legal boundaries and should not be used to provide a legal determination of land ownership.
</abstract><purpose>Parcels are a key framework data set for Hudson County's GIS spatial data network which serves the Hudson County information management system.</purpose><supplinf>
Although this data set does not contain property assessment information, each parcel record contains an attribute called the PAMS_PIN (a concatenation of the New Jersey Division of Taxation county/muncipality code, block number, lot number and qualification code) that uniquely identifies the parcel.  The PAMS_PIN field can be used to join the data set to MOD-IV database tables maintained by the New Jersey Division of Taxation that contain supplementary attribute information regarding lot ownership and characteristics.

This data set may not represent all current parcels because of lag in information flow and data development.
</supplinf></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20130521</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>publication date</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-74.986768</westbc><eastbc>-74.313491</eastbc><northbc>39.730015</northbc><southbc>39.288895</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Category</themekt><themekey>planningCadastre</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>NJGIN</themekt><themekey>njfw_cadastral</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>None</themekt><themekey>municipal</themekey><themekey>municipality</themekey><themekey>municipalities</themekey><themekey>county</themekey><themekey>parcel</themekey><themekey>parcels</themekey><themekey>lot</themekey><themekey>lots</themekey><themekey>block</themekey><themekey>blocks</themekey><themekey>boundary</themekey><themekey>boundaries</themekey><themekey>tax</themekey><themekey>assessment</themekey></theme><place><placekt>None</placekt><placekey>Hudson County</placekey><placekey>New Jersey</placekey><placekey>NJ</placekey><placekey>USA</placekey></place><temporal><tempkt>None</tempkt><tempkey>2008</tempkey><tempkey>2009</tempkey><tempkey>2010</tempkey><tempkey>2011</tempkey><tempkey>2012</tempkey><tempkey>2013</tempkey></temporal></keywords><accconst>none</accconst><useconst>
Hudson County and the State of New Jersey provide this product "as is".  The County and State make no guarantee, warranty or representations of any kind, including, but not limited to, the warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular use, nor are any such warranties to be implied with respect to the accuracy of information contained in the data.  The burden for determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user.

Although these data files have been successfully processed on computers at the County and State, no warranty is made by the County and State regarding the use of the data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply such a warranty.  The County and State assume no responsibility to maintain them in any manner or form.

This data set is not a survey document and should not be used as such.  The polygons delineated in this data set do not represent legal boundaries and should not be used to provide a legal determination of land ownership.
</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Hudson County Department of Planning</cntorg><cntper>Jason Bottcher</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>595 County Avenue, Bldg. 1, 2nd Floor</address><city>Secaucus</city><state>NJ</state><postal>07094</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(201) 217-5137</cntvoice><cntfax>(201) 795-7856</cntfax><cntemail>jbottcher@hcnj.us</cntemail><hours>M-F 9-4</hours></cntinfo></ptcontac><datacred>
Hudson County
New Jersey Meadowlands Commission, Meadowlands Environmental Research Institute
NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)
</datacred><secinfo><secsys>NJGIN</secsys><secclass>public</secclass><sechandl>no special handling required</sechandl></secinfo><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.3500</native><natvform>Shapefile</natvform></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Accuracy of linework and annotation was tested by visually comparing the digital data with the source materials.</attraccr></attracc><logic>This data set was created by merging municipal parcels data sets into one countywide data set.  Topology was created and checked.  Attributes were checked for database accuracy.</logic><complete>Data complete as per available information.</complete><posacc><horizpa></horizpa><vertacc></vertacc></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc>This digital data set was created by using scanned tax maps for all of the municipalities within Hudson County, New Jersey. The images were georeferenced to the 2002 color digital orthophotos for the state. Software customization was developed to standardize data capture as well as processing. Quality control/quality assurance methods were developed and used throughout the entire data capture and processing. GIS processing was done using ESRI's Arc Info 9.x and topology rules were applied to ensure proper connectivity between polygons. Each municipality was created individually and then combined into one county file at the end of the project.</procdesc><procdate>2008</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Civil Solutions</cntorg><cntper>Stephen Eckhardt</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Client Manager</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>800 S White Horse Pike, PO Box 579</address><city>Hammonton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08037-2019</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(800) 924-0482</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 704-8011</cntfax><cntemail>seckh@arh-us.com</cntemail><hours>8-5</hours></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>
As part of the New Jersey Office of Information Technology, Office of GIS (OGIS) effort to develop a statewide composite of parcel data sets, parcels sharing boundaries with municipal boundaries were modified to be coincident to the municipal boundaries data developed in 2008 by OGIS and adopted by GIS users throughout the state.  Parcel boundaries that cross municipal boundaries were also modified to properly align at and across the municipal boundary.

Three additional attribute fields were added to the attribute table to help note changes that occurred as a result of this process.  They include a field to store the original size of the parcel before editing, a field to store the percentage change in area size, and a field to code parcels that were significantly altered in size and/or shape.

After parcel geometry edits were completed, the area percentage change was calculated by comparing the size of the original area to the modified area using the following calculation, ([Shape_Area] / [OriginalAREA]) *100.  Each parcel with a value below 90 percent and above 110 percent was considered significant and reviewed more closely against 2007/2008 orthophotography and municipal tax maps to determine if the parcel modification was appropriate.

If, upon further inspection, the parcel modification was not consistent with the dimensions or acreage values shown on tax maps and/or orthophotography, the parcel (and neighboring parcels, if necessary) was again modified to minimize the size and/or shape distortion of the polygon.  After additional editing, the area change was recalculated.  If the recalculated change was still outside of the acceptable distortion level, the parcel was given a production code with an explanation for why the shape and/or area of the parcel was altered to a significant degree.  Definitions for the production codes were given to each data steward to assist in their review of the data.

The three additional attribute fields added to the attribute table to help note changes were deleted before final delivery of the data set to the data steward and OGIS.
</procdesc><procdate>2009</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Civil Solutions</cntorg><cntper>Stephen Eckhardt</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Client Manager</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>800 S White Horse Pike, PO Box 579</address><city>Hammonton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08037-2019</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(800) 924-0482</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 704-8011</cntfax><cntemail>seckh@arh-us.com</cntemail><hours>8-5</hours></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>In a continuing effort to improve parcels data quality, the New Jersey Office of Information Technology, Office of GIS (OGIS) and the County coordinated work to identify and fix duplicate PAMS_PIN records.  Most duplicates were related to condominium qualifier codes.  A much smaller proportion were due to incorrect data input and/or duplicate block and lot numbers on tax maps.</procdesc><procdate>201107</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Civil Solutions</cntorg><cntper>Stephen Eckhardt</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Client Manager</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>800 S White Horse Pike, PO Box 579</address><city>Hammonton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08037-2019</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(800) 924-0482</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 704-8011</cntfax><cntemail>seckh@arh-us.com</cntemail><hours>8-5</hours></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Parcel boundary and attribute data were updated  from the digital tax maps for Jersey City in February 2013 due to the new block/lot numbers that went into effect February 2012.  Quality control checks were performed to ensure proper closure of all boundary polygons.</procdesc><procdate>201302</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Civil Solutions</cntorg><cntper>Stephen Eckhardt</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Client Manager</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>850 S. White Horse Pike</address><city>Hammonton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08037</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(800) 924-0482</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 704-8011</cntfax><cntemail>seckh@arh-us.com</cntemail><hours>8-5</hours></cntinfo></proccont></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Corrections were made to parcel delineations to conform to the municipal boundary between Jersey City and North Bergen Twp, and along the Penhorn Creek (NJDEP hydro centerline) between Jersey City and Secaucus. A correction was also made to the parcel delineation of Ellis Island.

A modification was made to the municipal (nj_munis) boundary dataset between Jersey City and Hoboken as follows:

Jersey City:
block 3004 lot 1
block 2405 lot 2
block 4002 lot 1

Hoboken:
block 35 lots 4 &amp; 6
block 24 lots 1, 2, 4-6</procdesc><procdate>20130521</procdate><proccont><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NJOIT-OGIS</cntorg><cntper>Yelena Pikovskaya</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>PO Box 212</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625-0212</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>609.633.0420</cntvoice><cntfax>609.633.0200</cntfax><cntemail>yelena.pikovskaya@oit.state.nj.us</cntemail><hours>9-4</hours><cntinst>e-mail is preferred</cntinst></cntinfo></proccont></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>132030</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><mapproj><mapprojn>Transverse Mercator</mapprojn><transmer><sfctrmer>0.999900</sfctrmer><longcm>-74.500000</longcm><latprjo>38.833333</latprjo><feast>492125.000000</feast><fnorth>0.000000</fnorth></transmer></mapproj><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.000328</absres><ordres>0.000328</ordres></coordrep><plandu>survey feet</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic><cordsysn><geogcsn>GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><projcsn>NAD_1983_StatePlane_New_Jersey_FIPS_2900_Feet</projcsn></cordsysn></horizsys><vertdef><altsys><altres>0.000100</altres><altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc></altsys></vertdef></spref><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>parcels</enttypl><enttypd>New Jersey GIS Parcel Mapping Standard</enttypd><enttypds>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PAMS_PIN</attrlabl><attrdef>Concatenated Parcel Identification Number</attrdef><attrdefs>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Concatenated Parcel Identification Number</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>MUN</attrlabl><attrdef>Municipality code (NJ-1040)</attrdef><attrdefs>New Jersey Division of Taxation</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Municipality code (NJ-1040)</codesetn><codesets>New Jersey Division of Taxation</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>BLOCK</attrlabl><attrdef>Block number</attrdef><attrdefs>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Block number</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>LOT</attrlabl><attrdef>Lot number</attrdef><attrdefs>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Lot number</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>QCODE</attrlabl><attrdef>Qualifier code</attrdef><attrdefs>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Qualifier code</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>LASTUPDATE</attrlabl><attrdef>Date of last parcel edit</attrdef><attrdefs>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Date of last parcel edit</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</cntorg></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>PO Box 212</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625-0212</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(609) 633-9103</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 633-0400</cntfax><cntemail>njgin@oit.state.nj.us</cntemail><hours>M-F 9-4</hours></cntinfo></distrib><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>Distribution Liability: Hudson County and the State of New Jersey provide this product "as is".  The County and State make no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of information contained in the data.  Also, the County and State make no warranty, either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of the product or its fitness for any particular purpose.  The burden for determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user.  Although these data files have been successfully processed on computers at the County and State, no warranty is made by the County and State regarding the use of the data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply such a warranty.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>Filel Geodatabase Feature Class</formname><formvern>ArcGIS 10</formvern></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka></networka></computer></onlinopt></digtopt></digform><fees>none</fees></stdorder><techpreq>An ESRI desktop mapping client is required for use, such as ArcMap.</techpreq><availabl><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20130521</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></availabl></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20130521</metd><metrd>20130521</metrd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NJ Office of Information Technology (NJOIT), Office of Geographic Information Systems (OGIS)</cntorg><cntper>Douglas M. Schleifer</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>PO Box 212</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625-0212</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(609) 984-7544</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 633-0400</cntfax><cntemail>doug.schleifer@oit.state.nj.us</cntemail><hours>M-F 9-4</hours></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc><metac>none</metac><metuc>none</metuc><metsi><metscs>NJGIN</metscs><metsc>Public</metsc><metshd>no special handling required</metshd></metsi><metextns><onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns><langmeta>en</langmeta></metainfo></metadata>
